Venuprasad Naik

Senior Software Developer

A curious and experienced programmer with over four years and one month of experience in the software development field. With extensive experience in Java, Spring Framework, Oracle Cloud, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Kafka, Kubernetes, and Docker. I keep myself updated with new technologies and try to produce optimal code solutions. Received Young Achiever of the Year recognition at Mercedes-Benz Research and Development.

vpnaik97@gmail.com +91 72598 16840

linkedin.com/in/venuprasad

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oracle India Development Center

Senior Software Developer (Feb 2022 - Present)

- Part of Cloud Platform Engineering Team which delivers next generation multi-tenant platform of shared services.
- Tech Stack: Java, Spring Framework, Python, OCI, Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, Git, Helm
- Developed and Integrated Log Analytics for Ingress Traffic using Service Connector Hub, Logging Analytics, Python OCI SDK, Terraform

Mercedes-Benz Research and Development India

Consultant (Aug 2018 - Jan 2022)

- Contributed to the development of an in-house software application that operates 24x7 for ECU Development.
- Worked with cross competency teams to address business needs and system design. Technical solution design and development through implementation, usually focused on one module/system/service.
- Tech Stack: Core Java, Spring Framework, MS-SQL, Maven, JFrog, Jenkins, Git, SonarQube
- Developed IAM OIDC login for web applications using Spring Framework
- Worked on several backend code refactoring, optimisation and performance improvement tasks
- Developed maven library for parsing Metadata Exchange Format (MDX) and XML data from scratch
- Produced High-Quality software that has tested, code reviewed, analysed in sonar and checked in regularly for Continuous Integration
- Performing code reviews and checking for adherence to best practices and standard methodologies.
- Front End Developer for Developing a Web Application in React.js
 Framework with MobX.js and Axios.js
- Developed an Analytical and Monitoring application for providing cloud-based billing solution using React.js, JSON, Fluent UI

AquaSafi Purification Systems

Android Development Intern (Jun 2017 - May 2018)

- Built an Android Application from scratch for Water ATM using NFC, MifareClassic, ACR122u, java, SQLite, XML
- Developed OTP based Authentication for Android Application
- Worked on usage report generation and data sync to cloud

SKILLS

- Core Java
- Spring Framework
- Data Structure
- Oracle Cloud
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Kafka
- Git

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

B V B College of Engineering& Technology

Computer Science and Engineering

2014 - 2018

Hubli, Karnataka

CGPA: 8.58

CERTIFICATIONS

Problem Solving (Advanced)
Hacker Rank

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate Oracle

Advanced Java Programming LinkedIn

Data Structures & Algorithms edX with Georgia Tech